- [Instructor] This course, we'll use
the latest JavaScript syntax throughout.
And we want to be able to code our server
without worrying about any syntax breaking our application.
So Babel is the tool we'll set up to help
with compiling our code.
And let's also install the main dependencies
while we're at it.
So the first thing I'm going to do
is go inside of my backend folder first.
So the way we're going to do this
is go inside of our terminal.
So open up a new terminal.
And what I'm going to do first,
just to make sure I'm in the right directory,
which is the backend, I'm going to do an ls.
So clearly I'm not in the backend yet,
so I'm going to do cd backend.
And then in that particular directory,
I'm going to do an npm init.
Backend, version.
So I'm going to basically return all of these
to get my package.json file.
Yes. We're all good.
Then what I'm going to do is start installing
the dev dependencies.
So I'm going to do npm i
or you can do install --save-dev,
and I'm going to install a few dependencies.
The first one is babel/cli, so we can use it.
The second one is babel/core.
So we need the core code of Babel.
Then we need a particular package
that's called node in our case
because this is a node server.
And then, finally, just to make sure we have
the latest code covered for JavaScript,
we're going to do preset environment.
So I'm first going to install these dev dependencies.
Once this is done, you can check it very quickly.
Go to package.json,
you're going to see your dev dependencies right here.
Then what I'm going to do is install
the main dependencies that I need.
So, for this particular project,
we're going to need a few things,
and we're going to need and use all of these.
So, first, I'm going to do npm i or install.
I'm going to need body-parser
cors
express
mongoose
at nodemon.
We're going to need all of these.
And we'll install them ahead, like so.
Okay. So we installed all that we need.
If you look here on the package.json,
we have our dependencies and we have our dev dependencies.
Perfect.
So now what we're going to do,
inside of the backend folder,
we're going to create a new file that we'll call babel.rc.
So you want to make sure you're in that folder.
And you do .babelrc.
And just a quick note about this file.
In the exercise files,
if you can't see that particular file,
it's because it's hidden.
So you want to make sure that your system
shows hidden files.
Once you show hidden files,
you're going to be able to see that file.
So it's very important to do that.
And basically, it's going to be
very quickly set with presets,
and I need to load the @babel preset environment.
And that's pretty much what we need to set up
for our backend.
We'll keep working on it in the following videos.